Goodnight, Mister Tom is a drama, history, war film directed by Jack Gold.
A shy and quiet World War II evacuee is housed by a disgruntled
old man, and they soon develop a close bond.
Tom Oakley, played by John Thaw.
William Beech, played by Nick Robinson.
Mrs. Beech, played by Annabelle Apsion.
Zacharias Wrench, played by Thomas Orange.
Dr. Stelton, played by William Armstrong.
Vicar, played by Geoffrey Beevers.
Goodnight Mister Tom is a 1998 British film adaptation by Carlton
Television of the novel of the same name by Michelle Magorian.
The film is set during World War II and is about a young evacuee named William Beech who is placed in the care of a reclusive
widower, Tom Oakley, in a rural English village, where he gradually finds love and healing after escaping an abusive home.
It was Jack Gold's final film as a director.
The cast featured well-known British actors, including veteran actor John Thaw,
who played a bearded character for the first time in his career.
Filming took place during April and May 1998 in the village of
Turville, chosen due to practical and aesthetic reasons.
Critical reviews were mixed, with critics finding the story and conclusion of the film
predictable, although with praise for the cast performances, particularly Thaw.
The film explores themes of london, england, world war ii,
evacuation, based on children's book, dog.
The tone is emotional.